Have you ever heard about that
the cliff of a snow mountain
once fascinated numerous people?
Legend has it that,
there were treasures at the peak
but also there was a bottomless chasm hidden over there.
The smart, the fool
and the kind people,
all are familiar to you.
On the mountainside, on the cliff,
on the cloud,
and in the human world,
snowflakes are drifting profusely and disorderly.
Joy of Life Season 1
Episode 15
They all died.
Something must be going wrong.
If the commander committed suicide
because he colluded with the enemy,
how about his servants?
Why did they also do that?
He just received visitors in the study,
but they're gone.
It's all my fault.
If I had told you earlier
about this matter,
maybe they could've been saved.
The same thing would happen even if you had.
They want me to be here a little late.
Just a little late.
This is a warning. This is a threat.
It must be someone with supreme power
so that he can eradicate the whole
family of the commander in a flash.
How is it going at you side?
This is the token of the secret agent from Beiqi.
Token?
Beiqi has secret agents
that lurk in Nanqing.
They use tokens like this to deploy subordinates
and conduct activities.
In that sense,
Cheng Jushu is a Beiqi secret agent.
I'm afraid so!
What an honor to me!
This unknown big hand
unites Beiqi
just to kill me.
Your Excellency,
It's getting more and more complicated.
Do we still need to continue with it?
Yes, we do!
We can't let Teng Zijing die for nothing.
I'll never give up
before finding out the true killer.
But all the clues are ended now.
How is it going
with that big guy?
Why did you
fight him?
Where did you see him?
In a courtyard beside the stable
on Dashu Street.
Maybe not!
Let's forget about
the identity of the big hand behind the scene,
the involvement of the Beiqi secret agents,
the private sales of military supplies,
and the eradication of the commander's family.
What do we investigate then
if we forget them all?
Forget about all the non-essentials
and focus on the assassination itself.
Why did Cheng Jushu and the female assassinators
choose Niulan Street for the assassination?
You were heading towards Joy Tsin House
and would undoubtedly pass by Niulan Street.
How did they know it?
Perhaps they didn't.
They just followed secretly
and planned to do it by chance.
Not possible!
Two assassinators attacked from front
and back respectively that day.
Cheng Jushu hid at the back of the wall.
It was an ambush
well planned in advance.
They had known I would pass by Niulan Street well before it.
Who else knew
you were going to Joy Tsin House?
A lot of people could know that.
People from your residence?
They have nothing to do with it.
Is it possible that
they leaked it unintentionally?
Don't think too much.
The person who made the appointment with me naturally knew it.
The Second Prince?
He is under too much suspicion
to do it
which makes it seem deliberate.
Then there isn't any more suspect left.
Aren't you aware
since it was an appointment,
Joy Tsin House would need to
prepare the banquet in advance.
It's the people from Joy Tsin House?!
They also knew
I would pass by Niulan Street.
But Miss Si Lili and you
like each other so much.
People from her side
shouldn't have any problem.
I have no connection
with Si Lili.
In retrospect,
this Miss
doesn't look like
a courtesan in brothel at all.
So we need to go
to Joy Tsin House immediately.
Exactly!
Let me in!
No! No!
Sir, you can't come inside.
Why not?
Listen!
I made an appointment
with Miss Yunjian a long time ago.
What's the reason not to let me in?
There is no reason.
I must get in!
Sir!
You probably don't know that
Miss Si Lili's boat
has been burnt.
The government is investigating
the cause of the fire.
No one is allowed to go inside.
Please forgive us.
I didn't set up the fire.
I must go in.
Gentlemen, please!
Please don't go in there!
Excuse me, please!
Go! Go! Go!
Excuse me!
You said the boat got burnt?
When did that happen?
Sir, it was this noon.
It's such a pity
that a good boat got burnt
to ashes.
Where is Si Lili now?
She left!
Someone saw her going out of the city.
She must be frustrated
that the boat got burnt.
Gentlemen,
please come some other day.
Please...
Excuse us, please!
There is no clue
up to this point.
Your Excellency,
if we can find Si Lili,
there should be some clue.
Didn't you hear it?
She's gone for quite a while.
How do we find her?!
Maybe you don't know that
the Investigator's Office
has two masters of hunting.
One of them
is called Zong Zhui.
Generally, he follows the Head.
He is not in the capital city now.
As for the other one,
would you like to have a guess
who the other guy is?
Is that you?
I'm afraid yes.
It's surprising
that you are just a clerk with that skill.
Being a clerk is pretty good.
It runs no risk and therefore super safe.
Why do you help me?
Your Excellency,
I'm driven out
by the Investigator's Office now.
But my whole family
still needs sustenance.
I learned that by working for you,
I can earn 50 taels of silver a month,
and there is land and ox.
If you can really hunt her down for me,
I'll give you 10 extra pigs.
Fantastic!
Your Excellency,
my girl
loves pork belly best.
Are you really able to hunt her down?
That's not a problem to me.
The problem lies in you.
What do you mean?
Si Lili left the capital city so timely.
She could most likely
be the Beiqi secret agent
in view of it.
Her escape
must be a plan well in advance
so as to coordinate with the backup team.
If Your Excellency must hunt her down,
we must go out of the capital city
and run endless risks
to our lives.
Your Excellency,
are you willing to step on such a dangerous journey?
It was my brother who was murdered.
In that case,
please follow me to go out of the capital city
and start up this long journey.
Where are you going?
Where to?
Aren't we going out of here?
What do you want to do here?
All my equipment is at home.
I need to fetch them.
Is this your house?
Yes, it is.
Why don't you just walk in?
My wife is home. It's better to be careful.
Wang Qinian,
you're henpecked!
Your Excellency,
my wife has a nickname,
tigress-like Mrs. Wang.
What like?
Tigress.
Si Lili has gone for a while.
Let's hurry up.
It's fine!
It's easier to hunt
in day time.
My wife is deeply asleep.
Excuse me for a while.
I'll be back soon.
Please keep silent, Your Excellency!
Where are you going again, Wang Qinian?
Did you hide money in the case?
Listen to me, darling!
I've got business to do.
Done, Your Excellency!
It's done! Let's go!
Your Excellency!
Well done!
That's admiring.
Did you just say that
it's easier to hunt in day time?
Yes!
Then I also have a person to meet.
Why haven't you gone to bed?
I heard that you killed a man on the street.
I'm not fond of killing people.
That was to avenge Zijing.
Avenging friends is what man should do.
But today,
you're not here to see me.
How can you tell?
You didn't wear the nocturnal costume
or the perfume.
Wan'er,
Si Lili from Joy Tsin House
may have a hand
in the assassination.
She is at large out of the capital city.
I have to get her back.
You are leaving soon?
Yes, but I thought you'll be worried.
So here I am to say goodbye.
When will you be back?
As soon as I get her.
What if you don't?
I won't stop you
from what you want to do,
but it's impossible for me
not to worry.
Wan'er.
How about a hug before I leave?
It's dawn. I gotta go.
I'll be worried every day.
If you don't want me to,
come back.
The gate is open now.
It is the right time to go out.
Don't panic!
Your Excellency,
it's His Majesty's will
to let me kill Cheng Jushu.
Do you want to disobey His Majesty's will?
It is him that I am arresting.
Wang Qinian
secretly checked the confidential files.
According to the rule in the Investigator's Office,
he must be interrogated.
Here is the Director-General's token.
Who dare to touch him?!
The Director-General
shall also obey the rule in the Investigator's Office.
I designated Wang Qinian
to do it all.
You are still young.
I'm afraid you were cheated by him.
Take him!
Your Highness Earl Sinan!
Your Excellency, it's been a long time.
He is a kid and knows nothing.
Please forgive him for my sake.
I know it all about what happened to you.
What's the plan?
We're going out of the capital
city to hunt down the suspect.
These guards have special identity.
They can't go out without permission.
So I can't send anyone to go with you.
It's enough for just the two of us.
I'm really regretful
to have got you here.
Off you go!
Your dad is awesome.
These guards are imperial guards.
Even Prince Jing doesn't necessarily
have guards like that.
Your Excellency, the horses from just now
are military horses.
I know.
The Ministry of Revenue
should not have guards like that.
Should we get it investigated?
Those guards are most probably
guards for His Majesty.
That's a lot of trust from His Majesty to Earl Sinan.
The Head told us
before he left
that do not collide with Earl Sinan
unless it's national treason
or regicide.
That's very special treatment for an Assistant Minister.
The Assistant Minister of Ministry of Revenue
and the Head were serving His Majesty
ever since His Majesty was a crown prince.
That's very unusual friendship.
Assistant Minister of Ministry of Revenue Fan Jian
pays respects to Your Majesty!
Do you know why you are summoned here?
Yes, I do.
Say it!
I used the guards from Your Majesty
to stop the Investigator's Office.
Do you admit it's wrong?
I don't think it's wrong,
but if Your Majesty want to punish me for it,
I can take it.
Is it not wrong to go beyond your power?!
I indeed went beyond my power,
but that was to help Fan Xian
get out of the capital city,
which is to hunt down
the Beiqi secret agent,
Si Lili.
Who gave Fan Xian that power?
It is right Your Majesty!
I didn't issue that order.
Your Majesty surely didn't,
but as Your Majesty's servant, I should
be able to comprehend your will
even without an order.
If Your Majesty don't want Fan Xian
to handle this matter,
then you won't let him know
that Cheng Jushu was released.
And less likely to release him
after he killed Cheng Jushu.
Wang Qinian secretly checked the confidential
files of the Investigator's Office.
Zhu Ge wanted to convict him,
but also got suppressed by Your Majesty.
All of that
is to let Fan Xian go on with the investigation.
Done?
Not yet!
I have to talk about the cause as well.
Fan Xian has no titles.
Why do Your Majesty
want him to investigate it?
Your Majesty want to test his capability.
Once he gets married,
he will become the manager of Neiku
to manage all the assets and power.
There will be
lots of underwater competition by then.
He will mess it up if he is incapable.
Hunting down Si Lili
is a test
from which you can observe his judgement and actions.
What if your guess
is all wrong?!
I've been serving Your Majesty for so many years.
I believe my own judgement.
Besides, if I'm really wrong,
Your Majesty won't mind
in view of my loyalty
and my thoughtfulness to Your Majesty's will.
Does Fan Xian learn all his cunningness
from you?
I'm kind in nature
and can't take comments like that.
Kind in nature?
Do you think Fan Xian can catch her?
I bet he can!
You intend to make a bet with me?
I've been managing the Ministry of Revenue.
Calculating and gambling is my expertise.
Why you lose to your own son
in Pai Gow?
How do Your Majesty know this?
Can't I know it?
Yes, of course you can.
Your Majesty can have transparency
about all the things I do.
Your transparency?!
How about Fan Xian?
Well...
Your Majesty have to ask him on your own.
That depends on if he can catch the suspect.
Watch out!
I'm sorry!
Your Excellency,
they said they were on duty yesterday as well.
They saw Si Lili
fleeing out of town.
Which direction did she go?
To the north.
Then a few horses showed up.
The riders wear bamboo hats with similar dresses.
It's difficult to tell which one is Si Lili.
Then they went in their own separate ways.
So well-prepared they are!
What's wrong, Your Excellency?
Nothing.
I feel like something is not right.
What is it?
It's hard to say.
It could be the way
Si Lili escaped.
Multiple teams starting out together to create confusion.
That's a smart way to escape.
I know,
but still something is missed out.
Let's leave it!
How do you plan to hunt?
Your Excellency, please follow me.
=Investigator's Office=
Your Excellency, the pigeons fetched some messages again.
What are you doing?
Shoot a bird!
Where is the bird?!
It will come
in a minute.
Si Lili arranged six teams to go north
as the escaping plan.
Two of their whereabouts
have been captured by our regional secret agents.
The rest are being tracked.
Fan Xian must be after her out of the capital city.
It's not a concern
with his personal effort.
Si Lili will not
go out of our hands after all.
They would never expect
Your Excellency has detected it a long time ago
and sent different source of secret agents to investigate it.
Hunt down her teams one by one.
Don't let her escape out of Nanqing.
Yes!
There it goes!
A carrier pigeon?!
A carrier pigeon of the Investigator's Office.
Si Lili burnt the boat
and rode a horse out of town.
It must attract the attention
of the Investigator's Office.
Even though she arranged six teams,
her rough direction is to the north.
Most of the pigeons
from the north towns
will go through this place.
Si Lili is already being tracked.
Multiple teams are hunting her down.
Wait a minute! How do you know
the pigeons of the Investigator's Office
must go through here?
Honestly,
I have spent some time in the office
raising pigeons.
Won't it be noticed
that you shot their pigeon?
The Investigator's Office usually
sends out several pigeons in one go.
It's doesn't matter to have one of them missing.
Won't anyone notice it?
As pigeons usually come across predators like eagles
during their fly,
there is natural loss every month.
Besides,
I've raised pigeons for some time.
So I know
the number of pigeons coming back
always fluctuates.
No one will suspect.
What else have you raised other than pigeons?
Why do you ask so?
Save for a rainy day.
I must get prepared anyhow.
Here you go, sir! Tea for you!
Your Excellency,
I collected messages from different towns.
Two of the teams have been captured.
Neither of them is Si Lili.
The rest four teams are still being hunted.
How about Fan Xian? Is he still after her?
Fan Xian should not be able to catch up now.
Does Si Lili keep running towards the north?
Yeah, all the way north.
She should be heading to Beiqi.
Fetch the map!
Yes!
It's always passive to go from the behind.
As soon as we can figure out
where Si Lili
is running to,
we will be able to find the path
she has to go through.
Your Excellency, check this out!
This is a territory map I drew of
the mountains and rivers in the world.
This map
illustrates the scenic spots of the capital city in detail.
Two taels of silver.
It's super clear, isn't it?
I don't understand it at all.
Your Excellency, first of all,
we need to confirm
if Si Lili
is from Beiqi.
Her token as a secret agent is confirmed.
She is from Beiqi.
OK.
So she must go north.
But there are many ways
to go north.
But there are many military passes as well.
There aren't many ways
to go to Beiqi
without going through these passes.
Hold on a second.
What do these triangles
stand for?
Mountain ranges. Don't you understand?
How about these circles?
Can' you see that they are lakes?!
And these rectangles?
Some are big and some are small.
Big ones are castles.
Small ones are passes.
Can't you understand
all these signs?
Wang,
your drawing
is really extraordinary.
Your Excellency, I feel flattered.
That is to say,
Si Lili must go through this little town
since she wants to go to Beiqi quickly.
This town is the only way
to Beiqi.
If she chooses any other way,
it will take far more time.
I'll arrange
a tight encirclement right away
and gather all the secret agents here.
We'll surely capture Si Lili
and take her back to the capital city.
Off you go!
Yes!
Now that I can detect this,
so can
His Excellency Zhu.
I don't think we have time
to capture Si Lili.
But the Investigator's Office has a lot of ears.
They can capture
Si Lili for sure.
No, I must interrogate her in person.
Definitely!
We just need to
go north slowly
and intercept the team
that escorts Si Lili back to the capital city.
When it comes, just take out
your token as Director-General
and require them to hand over the suspect.
No one will dare to disobey.
Your Excellency, what's up?
I'm feeling a bit worried
ever since I came out of the capital city.
What you said just now
makes it even worse.
Did I say anything wrong?
I'm also wondering
your drawing is simple
but your words
are full of wisdom.
Your Excellency, let's keep going while talking.
Wait a minute. Let me think about
which sentence is it
that makes me feel not right.
I got it!
Si Lili burnt the boat
and rode a horse out of town.
It must attract the attention
of the Investigator's Office.
Even though she arranged six teams,
but her rough direction is to the north.
Is there anything wrong with that?
The description is right, but the story is not right.
Have you ever considered
why Si Lili had to escape?
She is involved in the assassination at Niulan Street.
Of course, she needs to escape as soon as she can.
Then why would she burn the boat?
The boat...
She wanted to escape. Then escape!
What's the point of burning the boat?
Perhaps there were confidential letters
on the boat.
Then just burn the letters.
Right! It would be enough to burn the letters.
Why did she burn the boat?
Second question.
Why would she ride a horse out of town
and arrange six teams?
Certainly, to create confusion.
What if she disguised herself
and went out of town secretly?
No one ever suspected her yesterday.
If she leaves secretly,
it would be far more difficult to find her.
But she still cut a splash
by burning the boat and taking
a horse which is eye-catching.
What's the purpose of that?
To let everyone know
she had left.
At that time point, everyone's attention
would be on the north of the capital city,
trying to figure out her escaping route.
If I were her,
it's the right time
to get disappeared
when everyone's attention is diverted.
That means
none of these six teams
has Si Lili in them.
The real Si Lili
has long lurked
outside of everyone's attention.
That's something hard to understand.
It makes sense
if she escapes silently.
Why did she do all that?
Because of the tension
between Nanqing and Beiqi at the moment.
War could break out any time soon.
What's the connection with that?
The security at the north must be very strict now.
It's not the right time for her to go.
There would be an equally lot of passes
which are equally strict
if she escapes secretly.
After she did all that,
the security at the north
will check more strictly.
So she doesn't necessarily go north.
Doesn't she go back to Beiqi?
She does!
Wang Qinian
is there any other way to Beiqi
without going north?
The way to Beiqi without going north?!
Isn't that...
There is indeed a way.
Tell me about it!
Instead of going north, go east directly.
Find the merchant ships and return to Beiqi by sea.
Which port is the most possible?
Dongyi Town! Oh no!
We have very strict security at Dongyi Town.
Besides, there are a lot of passes
on the way to Dongyi Town as well.
Other than that,
this would be the most possible place.
Your Excellency,
do you find this place familiar?
With your drawing like this,
how should I find it familiar? Just say it.
This is the place
Your Excellency grow up.
Danzhou harbor.
Yes, it is!
It's all within Nanqing
from the capital city to Danzhou harbor.
So it should be Danzhou harbor.
Check it out again!
From the north gate of the capital city
to Danzhou harbor,
which route is the most convenient?
What?
There is a lot of mountain ranges
and passes during the way
from the north gate to Danzhou harbor.
That's not an easy route either.
There is a simpler way.
What is it?
To return to the capital
and depart from the east gate.
To the east gate.
Stop!
Stand back!
Where are you going?
I'm seriously ill.
My hometown is said to have a famous doctor,
so I want to go there and have a try.
Go! Go! Go!
Thank you!
Stop!
You don't need to go back.
Move the carriage into the woods and burn it.
After that, leave to different directions
and don't leave any mark.
Yes!
According to Your Excellency's reasoning,
Si Lili may be ahead of us
for a short distance.
Indeed! Judging from their reaction,
Zhu Ge should find out
Si Lili's whereabouts today.
If she is patient enough,
she will wait for the Investigator's Office
to focus its attention all on the north
before she returns back to go eastwards.
Your Excellency's wisdom is indeed stunning.
I am totally shocked
by your extraordinary talent.
It gives me a constant sense of anxiety.
=Inn=
Excuse me,
feed my horse with premium forage
and give me a premium room.
Sure! This way please.
This is the room for you.
This way please.
Enjoy your stay!
Gentlemen, do you need accommodation?
No!
Yes!
Sure! Please come this way!
Your Excellency, let's have a look inside.
Come!
Sir, come this way!
Get us a good room!
Sure!
This is it.
Sir, that one is taken.
Come this way!
I'm sorry!
This room
faces the sun and it's spacious.
It's very cozy!
Your Excellency!
Do we really need the room?
Your Excellency, trust me!
After the long journey of hunting,
rest is more important than time.
Please!
Get us some hot water!
Sure! Please wait a moment!
How come Fan Xian is here?
Waiter!
Miss, what can I do for you?
Coming!
Sir, here comes the food for you.
Close the door!
Enjoy!
Your Excellency,
if Si Lili
really goes eastward,
we'll surely catch up with her
in two to three days.
She should have a horse.
Your Excellency,
if there is no backup horse,
she won't travel that fast with just one horse.
Just think about it!
The horse needs to take rests once in a while
when it is running.
And it has to be fed
with premium forage from time to time,
otherwise it will die
of fatigue.
The road we take
is actually a short cut between the hills
which is faster than the official road.
The shortest way is the straight line between two points.
What did you say?
Nothing!
Your Excellency,
will you pay
for the room and food?
Certainly!
Then it's not that weary!
Let's finish it!
Wait!
After you, Your Excellency!
It's poisonous!
Is it...
It seems we don't need to wait for two to three days.
It is made
by the kitchen.
Where did you fetch it after taken from the kitchen?
I fetched it directly to your room.
Who touched it in between?
No one!
Alright!
Then you're solely liable.
Come with me!
Look at him!
Look at him with your own eyes!
Don't you leave!
There is poison in the food and someone died with it.
What do we do now? I'll notify the imperial court!
No! No!
Well...
How could it happen?
I'm afraid you're the murder
in this case.
No! No! No!
It's not me! It's not me!
Didn't you say
only the kitchen and you touched the food?
Or this inn
is a sinister inn?
No! No!
A lady touched it!
Who is the lady?
She checked in this afternoon as well!
She insisted on
checking out the quality of the food here
before she decided whether to eat here or not.
So I brought your food box to her
to have a look.
I did nothing else.
Why did you pick ours in particular?
Because you live close!
Just the opposite side.
He is alive again!
In the river of history,
time goes round and round.
Memories about the former and present lives
join each other in an endless way.
In the long drunken Milky Way,
one season follows another in a flash,
and the wild geese are flying south.
I just can't give up
to be with you for my whole life.
I have been hovering in the dreams
for hundreds and thousands of times.
I can't even say a word when I watch the flowers falling.
Year after year in the wandering,
I count the remaining years.
Even though we can't meet each other anymore,
even though we have ended up the destiny,
I never feel regretful.
In such a chaotic world,
I still miss you as ever.
I can't fall asleep under the moon.
With a gentle heart,
I cherish our remaining years.
Even though we have to go through
all the hardships along the journey,
you always stay by my side,
watching the falling flowers, speechlessly.
Year after year in the wandering,
I count the remaining years.
Even though we can't meet each other anymore,
even though we end up the destiny,
I never feel regretful.
In such a chaotic world,
I still miss you as ever.
I can't fall asleep under the moon.
With a gentle heart,
I cherish our remaining years.
Even though we have to go through
all the hardships along the journey,
you always stay by my side...